Guide to the Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Field Work, Series VI
  - Records of Student Volunteer Unions and Groups
    - State and Regional Unions and Groups
      - Maine, 1932-1934 (Box 521, Folder 6127)
      - Maryland, 1936, 1948 (Box 521, Folder 6128)
      - Massachusetts, 1939 (Box 521, Folder 6129)
      - Michigan, 1921-1934 (Box 522, Folder 6130,6131)
      - Minnesota, 1927-1952 (Box 522, Folder 6132)
      - Mississippi, 1935 (Box 522, Folder 6133)
      - Missouri, 1925 (Box 522, Folder 6134)
      - Nebraska, 1924-1936 (Box 522, Folder 6135)
      - New England region (Box 522, Folder 6136)
      - New Jersey, 1892-1939 (Box 522, Folder 6137)
      - New York City, 1894- 1941 (Box 523, Folder 6138-6140)
      - New York State, 1897- 1934 (Box 523, Folder 6141,6142)
      - North Carolina, 1928-1939 (Box 523, Folder 6143)
      - Northern California, 1927,1928 (Box 523, Folder 6144)
      - Northern Ohio, 1924-192g (Box 523, Folder 6145)
      - Nova Scotia, 1928 (Box 523, Folder 6146)
      - Ohio, 1930-1954 (Box 523, Folder 6147)
      - Oklahoma, 1932-1952 (Box 524, Folder 6148)
      - Oregon, 1925-1932 (Box 524, Folder 6149)
      - Philadelphia, 1894, 1926 (Box 524, Folder 6150)
      - South Atlantic region, 1931-1935 (Box 524, Folder 6151)
      - South Carolina, 1908-1941 (Box 524, Folder 6152)
      - Southeastern region, 1944-1950 (Box 524, Folder 6153)
      - Southern California, 1927 (Box 524, Folder 6154)
      - Southern Ohio, 1928 (Box 524, Folder 6155)
      - Tennessee, 1928-1941 (Box 524, Folder 6156)
      - Texas, 1924-1936 (Box 524, Folder 6157)
      - Toronto, 1928 (Box 524, Folder 6158)
      - Tri-State (Delaware, Maryland, D.C.), 1924 (Box 524, Folder 6159)
      - Virginia, 1931-1952 (Box 524, Folder 6160)
      - Washington, 1922-1936 (Box 524, Folder 6161)
      - West Virginia, 1916-1952 (Box 524, Folder 6162)
      - West Virginia and Western Pennsylvana-, 1932-1942 (Box 524, Folder 6163)
      - Wisconsin, 1922 (Box 524, Folder 6164)
      - Oversize scrapbook South Atlantic region, 1930-1931 (Box Ov16)
- Publications and Literature Distribution, Series VII
  The Student Volunteer Movement had a message which it wanted to communicate to students on North American college and university campuses. Early in its existence it discovered that one of the most effective means of communicating its message was through the publication and distribution of periodicals, pamphlets and books. Even during the years when the Movement's role on local campuses was questioned, its mandate to produce missions-related literature remained clear. The over fourteen linear feet of records in Series VII are divided in five sections:
  A. Literature Committee records
  The correspondence, meeting minutes and other administrative papers in this section date from approximately 1940 to 1960. Also included in this section are a folder of literature copyright records (1913-1937), a folder of orders for literature not published by the SVM, and several record books dating from 1927 to 1952.
  B. Literature distribution correspondence
  1. General records: The material in this section is topically arranged and includes literature inventories, accounts, orders, etc.
  2. Literature distribution correspondence: The letters in this section date from approximately 1916 to 1957. They are in general alphabetical order, according to the name of the individual or organization requesting or inquiring about a SVM publication.
  C. Prospective publications
  The material in this chronologically arranged file includes manuscripts, reviews, correspondence, and notes related to actual or possible SVM publications. The title of the prospective publication is noted in addition to the dates when it was under consideration.
  D. Periodical publications
  The major periodical publications of the Student Volunteer Movement were as follows:
  The Student Volunteer (1893-1898)
  The Intercollegian (1898-1912; published jointly with the YMCA)
  The North American Student (1913-19; published jointly with the YWCA)
  Student Volunteer Movement Bulletin (1915-1930)
  Far Horizons ( 1930-1934)
  Intercollegian and Far Horizons (1934-1939; published with the YMCA)
  Intercollegian 1939-1959; published with the YMCA and YWCA)
  These periodicals were issued at varying frequencies and were supplemented at certain times with less substantial offerings such as the Fellowship News. During the 1940s and 1950s the SVM also published a semi-annual listing of missionary vacancies entitled Christian Horizons. After the SVM became the Commission on World Mission of the National Student Christian Federation, the Committee on the Fellowship of Student Volunteers produced
  a newsletter, for which copies are available through 1964. The bulk of the material in this section is related to the more recent
  periodicals published by the SVM, Far Horizons and Christian Horizons. Thematerial consists primarily of correspondence to arrange for articles and to maintain subscriptions. The series is arranged alphabetically, by the title of the publication.
  E. Pamphlet Publications
  Copies of many of the pamphlets published by the Student Volunteer Movement are available in this section, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Literature Committee Records
    - Publishing records, ca. 1904-1922 (Box Ov7)
    - Record of literature sold, ca. 1932-1938 (Box Ov9)
    - Records of literature and forms printed, 1927-1929 (Box Ov16)
    - Records of literature and forms printed, 1929-1930 (Box Ov13)
    - Records of literature and forms printed, 1930-1931 (Box Ov15)
    - Records of literature and forms printed, 1931-1935 (Box Ov3)
    - Records of literature and forms printed, 1952 (Box Ov13)
    - Minutes, communications, 1940-1960, n.d. (Box 525, Folder 6165-6170)
    - Literature copyrights, 1913-1937 (Box 525, Folder 6171)
    - Orders for non-SVM publications, 1941-1944 (Box 525, Folder 6172)
  - Literature Distribution
    - General Records
      - Audio-visual materials, 1945-1956 (Box 525, Folder 6173)
      - Book lists, bibliographies, form letters, 1932-1937 (Box 525, Folder 6174)
      - Budgets, accounts, 1937-1943 (Box 525, Folder 6175)
      - Consignment and conference distribution, 1940-1953 (Box 525, Folder 6176,6177)
      - Literature inventories, 1908-1927 (Box 525, Folder 6178)
      - Literature inventories, 1928-1956 (Box 526, Folder 6179)
      - Re. liquidation of SVM library, 1950 (Box 526, Folder 6180)
      - Re. pamphlet for Christian Reconstruction Committee, 1942 (Box 526, Folder 6181)
    - Literature distribution correspondence
      - Aa - Ar (Box 526, Folder 6182-6189)
      - As - Bl (Box 527, Folder 6190-6198)
      - Bo - Cas (Box 528, Folder 6199-6210)
      - Cat - De (Box 529, Folder 6211-6224)
      - Di - Fi (Box 530, Folder 6225-6236)
      - Fl - He (Box 531, Folder 6237-6247)
      - Hi - Ki (Box 532, Folder 6248-6259)
      - N - Ma (Box 533, Folder 6260-6272)
      - Me - N (Box 534, Folder 6273-6283)
      - 0 - Re (Box 535, Folder 6284-6296)
      - Ri - Sp (Box 536, Folder 6297-6311)
      - St - V (Box 537, Folder 6312-6326)
      - Wa - Z (Box 538, Folder 6327-6343)
  - Prospective Publications
    - "History of the Student Volunteer Movement"; J. R. Mott, 1892 (Box 539, Folder 6344)
    - "The Volunteer Declaration"; D.W. Lyon, 1895 (Box 539, Folder 6345)
    - "Twentieth Anniversary of the SVM", 1906 (Box 539, Folder 6346)
    - "Ba Thane"; E. Baldwin, 1934-1948 (Box 539, Folder 6347)
    - "Operation at One", 1935 (Box 539, Folder 6348)
    - "Students and the Christian World Mission", 1936 (Box 539, Folder 6349)
    - "The Measure of a Modern Missionary"; W. Wysham, 1937 (Box 539, Folder 6350)
    - "Letters by a Modern Mystic"; F. Laubach, 1937-1957 (Box 539, Folder 6351-6353)
    - "The Christian Church in Nigeria"; S. U. Etuk, 1939 (Box 539, Folder 6354)
    - "Christianity in China"; P. C. Hsu, 1939 (Box 539, Folder 6355)
    - "In This Generation"; R. Braisted, 1941-1942 (Box 539, Folder 6356)
    - "A Mission to the U.S.A."; R. Benfer, 1944 (Box 539, Folder 6357)
    - "How to Become a Missionary", 1945 (Box 539, Folder 6358)
    - "Make Up Your Life... ", 1945-1950 (Box 539, Folder 6359)
    - "A Philosophy of Life That Works"; W. Judd, 1945-1952 (Box 539, Folder 6360)
    - "SVM Handbook", 1947 (Box 539, Folder 6361)
    - "Student Volunteer Movement Bulletin", 1948 (Box 539, Folder 6362)
    - "Careers in the Christian Mission", 1948-1955 (Box 539, Folder 6363)
    - "Literature on the Christian World Mission", 1949-1959 (Box 539, Folder 6364)
    - "The College Student and the Missionary Obligation"; T. Jones, 1950 (Box 540, Folder 6365)
    - "Student Vdhnteers for 1950"; R. Seabury (Box 540, Folder 6366)
    - "Students Ask About Missions", 1950-1951 (Box 540, Folder 6367-6372)
    - "That They May Have Life"; D. T. Niles, 1950-1951 (Box 540, Folder 6373-6375)
    - "For This Hour"; E. Johnson, 1951 (Box 541, Folder 6376)
    - "That All May Be One"; L. Newbigin, 1951-1952 (Box 541, Folder 6377)
    - "SVM Today", 1951-1956 (Box 541, Folder 6378)
    - "Campus Christians and the World Mis- sign"; F. Cooley, 1954 (Box 541, Folder 6379,6380)
    - "Jobs on Your Doorstep", 1955 (Box 541, Folder 6381)
    - "Mrs. Missionary"; M. Copland, 1956-1957 (Box 541, Folder 6382)
    - "Reconciliation and Renewal in Japan"; M. Tekenaka, 1956-1957 (Box 541, Folder 6383)
    - "Multitudes in the Valley"; D. Baly, 1957-1959 (Box 541, Folder 6384)
    - "The Halting Kingdom: Christianity and the African Revolution", J. Karefa-Smart, 1957-1959 (Box 541, Folder 6385)
    - "Outside the Camp"; C. West, 1957-1960 (Box 542, Folder 6386-6388)
    - "The Life and Mission of the Church in America", 1958 (Box 542, Folder 6389)
    - "Missionary Vocation"; K. Bridston, 1958 (Box 542, Folder 6390)
    - "Threefold Mission of the Church"; W. Visser 't Hooft, 1958-1959 (Box 542, Folder 6391)
    - "SVM and the National Student Christian Federation", c. 1959 (Box 542, Folder 6392)
    - "Raise a Signal"; H. Converse, 1960-1961 (Box 542, Folder 6393-6395)
    - "Servants of God in People's China"; K. Hockin, 1961 (Box 542, Folder 6396)
    - "The Noise of Solemn Assemblies"; P. Berger, 1961 (Box 543, Folder 6397,6398)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, n.d. (Box 543, Folder 6399,6400)
  - Periodical Publications
    - Christian Horizons, 1943-1947 (Box 543, Folder 6401-6406)
    - Christian Horizons, 1948-1950 (Box 544, Folder 6407-6415)
    - Christian Horizons, 1950-1954 (Box 545, Folder 6416-6423)
    - Christian Horizons, 1955-1957 (Box 546, Folder 6424-6428)
    - Far Horizons: Book reviews, 1930-1935 (Box 546, Folder 6429)
    - Far Horizons: Form letters, 1930-1934 (Box 546, Folder 6430)
    - Far Horizons: Reports, 1930-1934 (Box 546, Folder 6431)
    - Far Horizons: Re. student editorial board, 1933 (Box 546, Folder 6432)
    - Far Horizons: Subscriber comments, 1931-1932 (Box 546, Folder 6433)
    - Far Horizons: Manuscripts submitted, 1932-1934 (Box 546, Folder 6434)
    - Far Horizons: Engraved blocks for photos and graphics (Box 546A)
    - Far Horizons: Subscriptions, 1930-1931 (Box 547, Folder 6435-6440)
    - Far Horizons: Subscriptions, 1931 (Box 548, Folder 6441-6446)
    - Far Horizons: Subscriptions, 1932 (Box 549, Folder 6447-6453)
    - Far Horizons: Subscriptions, 1932-1933 (Box 550, Folder 6454-6457)
    - Horizons Abroad, 1942-1943 (Box 550, Folder 6458)
    - The Intercollegian: Administration and distribution, 1938-1953; n.d. (Box 550, Folder 6459-6463)
    - The Intercollegian: Content, 1938-1953; n.d. (Box 551, Folder 6464-6473)
    - The Intercollegian and Far Horizons: Administration and distribution, 1934-1940 (Box 551, Folder 6474-6476)
    - The Intercollegian and Far Horizons: Content, 1934-1939 (Box 551, Folder 6477-6478)
    - Newsletter of the Fellowship of Student Volunteers for Christian Mission, 1960-1964 (Box 552, Folder 6479-6481)
    - Recruiting Information Service, 1940-1941 (Box 552, Folder 6482)
    - SVM Fellowship News, 1934-1936 (Box 552, Folder 6483)
    - The Student Volunteer Fellowship of Prayer, 1941-1942 (Box 552, Folder 6484-6485)
    - The Student Volunteer Movement Bulletin, 1921-1930 (Box 552, Folder 6486)
    - Student Volunteer Movement Newsletter, 1949-1959 (Box 553, Folder 6487-6491)
  - Pamphlet Publications
    - Abbu and Company; The Achievements of the SVM for Foreign Missions,1886-1919; Adventure, History, Faith; The Agricultural Missionary; Agriculture in the Program of Modern Missions; The Aim and Motive of Foreign Missions (Box 554, Folder 6492)
    - Allies of the Truth; The America and Canadian Student in Relation to the Worldwide Expansion of Christianity; The American Student Missionary Uprising; Another Chapter in Our History; An Appeal from China (Box 554, Folder 6493)
    - An Appeal from Japan; An Appeal to the Christian Medical Students of America; An Appeal to the Churches; Are More Foreign Missionaries Needed?; Are More Missionaries Needed and Wanted? (Box 554, Folder 6494)
    - Are More Missionaries Wanted in China?; Ba Thane: A One-Act Play of Burma; Benefits Derived From Mission Study; The Bible and Foreign Missions (Box 554, Folder 6495)
    - The Blue and the Red Triangles; Builders of a Rural Civilization; Building a World Christian Community; C.B.R. of Chungking; A Call for Colleagues (Box 554, Folder 6496)
    - A Call for Leadership; A Call for a Moment of Destiny; A Call to Prayer Careers in the Christian Mission; Careers of International Service The Case for Foreign Missions; China After the War (Box 554, Folder 6497)
    - The Christian Enterprise Abroad; The Christian Message; The Christian Message for a Bewildered World The Christian Ministry Overseas (Box 554, Folder 6498)
    - The Christian Mission in the World of Today; Christian Missions; Christian Missions in World Perspective (booklist); Christian Service Abroad (Box 554, Folder 6499)
    - Christianity and the Non-Christian Religions; Christianity the Forerunner of Democracy; Church Social Worker; Circle of Prayer for Volunteers; The College Woman's Opportunity (Box 554, Folder 6500)
    - Comparative Studies in Missionary Biography; Consecration; Course of Study on Medical Missions; Cycle of Prayer (Box 554, Folder 6501)
    - Declaration Card; Declaration of Purpose; Detained but Dauntless; A Doctor's Reasons for Going to China (Box 554, Folder 6502)
    - Economic Problems and the Christian Ideal; The Educational Missionary; Educational Specialists; Exhibit of Missionary and Allied Literature (catalogue); Factors in the Development of the SVM; Facts About the SVM (Box 554, Folder 6503)
    - The Field Campaign for Missions; Fields Still Unoccupied The First Essential of Brotherhood; The First Two Decades of the SVM (Box 554, Folder 6504)
    - Fundamental Qualifications of the Foreign Missionary; General Suggestions for Leaders of Mission Study Classes (Box 554, Folder 6505)
    - General Suggestions to Leaders of Mission Classes; Get Ready for a Real Job (Box 554, Folder 6505)
    - God Through Life or Life Through God?; Great Achievement for Which We are Thankful; Handbook, Fourth International Convention; Handbook of the SVM (Box 554, Folder 6506)
    - Hints on Mission Study Class Methods; History of the SVM (1892); Home Ties and the Foreign Mission Field; How Many New Missionaries are Needed? (Box 554, Folder 6507)
    - How Shall They Hear?; How to Find Reality in Your Morning Devotions (Box 554, Folder 6508)
    - Hymnals: 1898, 1901 (Box 555, Folder 6509)
    - Hymnals: 1902, 1906 (Box 555, Folder 6510)
    - Hymnals: 1909-1910, 1919-1920 (Box 555, Folder 6511)
    - Hymnals: 1923-1924, 1927, 1931-1932 (Box 555, Folder 6512)
    - I am a Christian; If God Permit; Industrial Education Among Primitive Peoples; The Impending Struggle in Western Asia (Box 555, Folder 6513)
    - The Influence and Results of the SVM; Intercessory Foreign Missionaries; Is Mission Study Worth While?; Is the Missionary Door Shut? (Box 555, Folder 6514)
    - Is There a Plan for My Life?; Japan and Reconstruction (Box 555, Folder 6515)
    - Jerusalem Answer to Present Day Inquiries; Jerusalem's Challenge; Jobs on Your Doorstep (Box 555, Folder 6515)
    - Latin America's Place in World Life; Letters by a Modern Mystic; Literature on the Christian World Mission; Looking Ahead in Malaysia (Box 555, Folder 6516)
    - Making Christ Known the World Around; Measure of a Modern Missionary; The Medical Advance Guard; The Medical Missionary (Box 555, Folder 6517)
    - A Medical Question-Box; The Message and the Man; A Message to Student Volunteers for Foreign Missions; The Minister in Missions (Box 555, Folder 6518)
    - Mission Study (Prospectus) 1904-1905 yearly to 1910-1911 (Box 555, Folder 6519)
    - Mission Study (Prospectus) 1911-1912 through 1918-1919 (Box 555, Folder 6520)
    - Mission Study Among Theological Students; Mission Study Class Mission Study Class Method The Missionary Demand and Supply; The Missionary Life of the Theological Seminary (Box 555, Folder 6521)
    - Missionary Meetings; The Missionary Nurse; Missionary Programs for Schoolboys; The Missionary Social Worker; The Missionary Uprising Among Students; The Missionary Wife; Missions in the New Age (Box 556, Folder 6522)
    - Modern World Movements: God's Challenge to the Church (Box 556, Folder 6523)
    - Money: Its Nature and Power Motives in Foreign Missions; A Movement with a History Faces a New Day; Mrs. Missionary (Box 556, Folder 6523)
    - My Place in the World's Work; Near East: A Discussion Course for Students; New Days for the Philippines; The New Era in the Near East (Box 556, Folder 6524)
    - New Missionaries Needed and Wanted; Trails to World Friendship; The Non-Christian Religions Inadequate Not Leaders, But Saints and Servants (Box 556, Folder 6525)
    - The Nurse in the Mission FieId; Occasional Types of Missionaries On Your Mark! Get Set!; Operation at One: A One-Act Play of China; Opportunities Unlimited (Box 556, Folder 6526)
    - The Opportunity for Student Volunteers in the Present Crisis The Opportunity of the Hour; The Organization of Mission Study Among Students; Other Men's Shoes (Box 556, Folder 6527)
    - The Personal Factor; A Philosophy of Life that Works; Physical Fitness and Foreign Service; Posters and Poster-Making (Box 556, Folder 6528)
    - Prayer and Missions; Prayers for Missions; Preparation for Missionary Service; Present Conditions in China (Box 556, Folder 6529)
    - Publications of the SVM 1893, 1900-1913 (Box 556, Folder 6530)
    - Publications of the SVM 1916-1924; n.d. (Box 556, Folder 6531)
    - The Qualifications of the Foreign Missionary; A Question Box for Missionary Educators; A Question Box for Nurses; The Question of the Church in the World of Today; Racial Relations and the Christian Ideal; A Reading Course on India (Box 556, Folder 6532)
    - Record of the SVM 1911, 1912, 1914-1915, 1916; Recreational Songs (Box 556, Folder 6533)
    - Release: A Pageant; Religions of the World; The Rural Missionary
    - Scripture Principles of Giving Illustrated; Secret Prayer: A Great Reality; The Secular Press and Foreign Missions; A Selected Bibliography of Missionary Literature (Box 556, Folder 6534)
    - A Selected Bibliography of Recent Books; A Selected Bibliography on World Christianity; The Self-Perpetuation of the Volunteer Band; Shall I Go? (Box 556, Folder 6535)
    - Shall the Tent-Makers Preach?; Short Course of Reading; Since India Went Over the Top; Some Atheisms to Which a Missionary Seems Susceptible (Box 557, Folder 6536)
    - A Spiritual Awakening Among India's Students; Spiritual Prerequisites; Student Missionary Deputations Among the Churches and Young People's Societies; Student Vision of the World-wide Church; The Student Volunteer Fellowship of Prayer (Box 557, Folder 6537)
    - The Student Volunteer Movement (various pamphlets) (Box 557, Folder 6538)
    - The SVM After 25 Years (Box 557, Folder 6539)
    - SVM Announcements (1897-98)
    - SVM Becomes the Commission on World Mission, NSCF; The SVM for Foreign Missions; The SVM for Home Missions (Box 557, Folder 6539)
    - The SVM in a Day of Growing Imperatives; The SVM in Canadian Colleges; The SVM Indicator; The SVM: Its Origin and Early History; The SVM Looks Ahead (Box 557, Folder 6540)
    - SVM Study Manual (Box 557, Folder 6541)
    - The SVM:1943-1944; Students and Missions; Students and the Christian World Mission; Students Ask About Missions (series of 8 pamphlets); The Students of North America in Relation to the Non-Christian World (Box 557, Folder 6542)
    - The Student's Part in a Troubled World; Studentenbund fur Mission; Suggestions for the Visit of a SVM Traveling Secretary; Suggestions to Student Volunteers; The Supreme Decision (Box 557, Folder 6543)
    - The Task of Tomorrow in Africa; Ten Lessons on the Bible and Missions (Box 557, Folder 6544)
    - Ten Reasons Why the SVM Merits Your Help in 1931; Things That Last in Christian Missions (Box 557, Folder 6544)
    - To Be a Missionary, A.D., 1946; Training for Non-Theological Missionaries; Transplantings; Unevangelized Areas (Box 557, Folder 6545)
    - United Intercessions; The Urgency and Crisis in the Far East (Box 557, Folder 6546)
    - The Value of Mission Study to the Normal School Student; A Vision Realized (Box 557, Folder 6546)
    - The Volunteer Declaration; Volunteer Missions Band; The Volunteer Pledge; Wanted --Authors (Box 557, Folder 6547)
    - Wanted: Renewal in Mission; Wanted: Student Volunteers; The Watchword as a Spiritual Force; Weekly Prayer Cycle for Leaders of Mission Study Classes (Box 557, Folder 6548)
    - What About Missions?; What Can I Believe About Christian Missions?; What Constitutes a Missionary Call? What Future? (Box 557, Folder 6549)
    - What Is Involved in Mission Study; What is Involved in Signing the Declaration of the SVM; What is the SVM?; What Kind of Colleagues?; We Have Failed (Box 558, Folder 6550)
    - While the Clay is on the Wheel; Who is Qualified to Prepare(for Foreign Missionary Service)?; Why Fiddle? Rome Burns!; Why I Study Missions (Box 558, Folder 6551)
    - Why Leave Non-Christian America for the Orient?;` Why Theological Training for Missionaries? (Box 558, Folder 6552)
    - Windows to a World Outlook; A Woman's Life and the World's Work; The Wonderful Challenge to this Generation of Christians; Working Abroad as a Christian (Box 558, Folder 6552)
    - The World Enterprise of Christianity (Study Course 1919-1922); A World Fellowship Book Shelf (Book List; 1925-1926, 1928); A World Horizon for Students; The World Mission of Christianity (Box 558, Folder 6553)
    - The World's Need; World-Wide Christian Outlook; You Will Be Glad; Youth and Renaissance Movements; Youth and the Human Scene (Box 558, Folder 6554)
- Conventions, Series VIII
  The quadrennial conventions of the Student Volunteer Movement were the highpoints of its corporate existence. It was during these gatherings that the meaning and value of the Movement seemed most clear. The stated objectives of the first convention held in Cleveland in 1891 were 1) to allow for discussion of any problems facing the Movement; 2) to provide opportunities for student volunteers to meet with missions board secretaries and returned missionaries; 3) to enlighten missions board secretaries and others regarding the work of the Movement, and 4) to give new impetus to the missionary cause.(SVM Archives, Series VIII, Cleveland 1891, Convention report, p. 3.) The sixteen quadrennial conventions which followed Cleveland varied in their points of emphasis but essentially held to these four objectives.